Guide to the Sir Thomas Tyrwhitt, Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
[Papers]
1796-1830
OSBORN FC112
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
0.15
(1 volume)
Autograph items and copies. Collection of letters and documents from his papers, chiefly relating to his service to the Prince of Wales, later George IV, king of Gt. Brit. (1762-1830).
Tyrwhitt, Thomas, 1762 or 1763-1833
Immediate Source of Acquisition
For provenance information, consult the appropriate curator.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
The following finding aid is a complete inventory of the contents of Osborn fc112. This list was reformatted from previously existing cataloging.
Letters; Nobility -- Great Britain; Great Britain -- Court and courtiers; Great Britain -- Foreign relations -- 1800-1837; Great Britain -- Politics and government -- 1800-1837; Great Britain -- Social life and customs -- 19th century; George, King of Great Britain, IV, 1762-1830; Napoleon, Emperor of the French, I, 1769-1821; Tyrwhitt, Thomas, 1762 or 1763-1833; Wraxall, Nathaniel William, Sir, 1751-1831
- OSBORN FC112
  - ARBUTHNOT, CHARLES, 1767-1850
    - ALS to Sir Nathaniel William Wraxall, 1st bart. (1751-1831), 1813 Feb 2 (Box 1)
      Scope and Contents
      Downing Street
      2 p.; 18 x 11 cm.
      Robert Banks Jenkinson, 2nd earl of
      Liverpool (1770-1828), does not
      approve of Wraxall's claim to a
      baronetcy.
      112/11
  - BALCOMBE, WILLIAM, 1779-1829
    - ALS to Sir Thomas Tyrwhitt (1763-1833), 1815 Oct 15 (Box 1)
      Briers
      3 p.; 23 x 18 cm.
      On Sir George Cockburn (1763-1847)
      and the provisioning of Napoleon I,
      emperor of the French (1769-1821),
      on St. Helena.
      112/22a and b
  - BALCOMBE, WILLIAM, 1779-1829
    - Letter (copy) to Sir Thomas Tyrwhitt (1763-1833), 1815 Oct 20 (Box 1)
      Description of Napoleon I, emperor
      of the French (1769-1821), on St.
      Helena.
      112/23
  - BARRINGTON, WILLIAM BARRINGTON-SHUTE, 2ND BARON, 1717-1793
    - ALS to unnamed recipient, 1771 Dec 23 (Box 1)
      Cavendish Square
      1 p.; 24 x 18 cm.
      Acknowledges that Sir Thomas
      Tyrwhitt (1763-1833) did not accept
      an offered position.
      112/68
  - BATHURST, HENRY BATHURST, 3RD EARL, 1762-1834
    - ALS to Sir Thomas Tyrwhitt (1763-1833), 1829 Aug 12 (Box 1)
      n.p.
      On the Privy Council.
      112/66
  - BEDFORD, JOHN RUSSELL, 6TH DUKE OF, 1766-1853
    - ALS to Sir Thomas Tyrwhitt (1763-1833), 1827 Jan 13 (Box 1)
      Earlshigh
      4 p.; 18 x 12 cm.
      Sympathy for his illness.
      112/73
  - BEDFORD, JOHN RUSSELL, 6TH DUKE OF, 1766-1853
    - ALS to Sir Thomas Tyrwhitt (1763-1833), 1827 May 10 (Box 1)
      Regrets missing him and discusses
      personal matters.
      112/72
  - BEDFORD, JOHN RUSSELL, 6TH DUKE OF, 1766-1853
    - ALS to Sir Thomas Tyrwhitt (1763-1833), [1827] Aug 3 (Box 1)
      Informing Tyrwhitt of his departure
      on the 12th and expresses his regret
      at missing Tyrwhitt's impending
      visit.
      112/74
  - BAILLIE, E.
    - ALS to Sir Thomas Tyrwhitt (1763-1833), n.d. (Box 1)
      1 p.; 18 x 11 cm.
      Note sent with enclosed music.
      112/67
  - BRIDGES, GEORGE
    - ALS to Sir Thomas Tyrwhitt (1763-1833), [ca. 1820] (Box 1)
      Mansion House
      Demands his support on the Committee
      of Orthodox Churchmen.
      112/44
  - BURGESS, THOMAS, 1756-1837
    - ALS to Sir Thomas Tyrwhitt (1763-1833), 1798 Mar 6 (Box 1)
      Durham
      Request for his uncle's notes on
      Aristophanes.
      112/69
  - CANNING, GEORGE, 1770-1827
    - LS to Sir Thomas Tyrwhitt (1763-1833), 1825 Apr 21 (Box 1)
      Foreign Office
      2 p.; 32 x 19 cm.
      Informs Tyrwhitt that he is to be
      sent to Paris to attend the
      investment in the Order of the
      Garter of Louis Philippe, king of
      the French (1773-1850).
      112/41
  - CLANWILLIAM, RICHARD CHRISTIAN MEADE, 3RD EARL OF, 1795-1879
    - ALS to Sir Thomas Tyrwhitt (1763-1833), 1822 Feb 22 (Box 1)
      On his being granted passage to and
      from Lisbon with Sir Edward Thornton
      (1766-1852) by Charles William Vane,
      3rd marquis of Londonderry
      (1778-1854).
      112/38
  - CLANWILLIAM, RICHARD CHRISTIAN MEADE, 3RD EARL OF, 1795-1879
    - ALS to Sir Thomas Tyrwhitt (1763-1833), 1822 (Box 1)
      2 p.; 23 x 18 cm.
      Informs of the government's decision
      not to send the Order of the Garter
      to John VI, king of Portugal
      (1769-1826) as had been originally
      planned.
      112/39
  - CLARENDON, JOHN CHARLES VILLIERS, 3RD EARL OF, 1757-1838
    - ALS to Sir Thomas Tyrwhitt (1763-1833), 1830 Jan 19 (Box 1)
      Walford
      4 p.; 18 x 11 cm.
      Agrees to be named Chairman of the
      Rupture Society.
      112/79
  - COLLINGWOOD AND LUCAS, CARRIAGE-MAKERS
    - Bill to the Prince of Wales, later George IV, king of Gt. Brit. (1762-1830), 1799 May-Sep (Box 1)
      14 p.; 37 x 23 cm. Itemized bill for the sum of £1219.14.5. 112/199
  - COURCY, SIR JOHN
    - ALS to Sir Thomas Tyrwhitt (1763-1833), 1820 Mar 3 (Box 1)
      Kensington Palace
      Appeal for a position for Sergeant
      Rogers.
      112/50
  - COWLEY, HENRY WELLESLEY, 1ST BARON, 1773-1847
    - ALS to Sir Thomas Tyrwhitt (1763-1833), 1829 May 15 (Box 1)
      Regents Park
      3 p.; 18 x 11 cm.
      Recommends his servant for
      consideration.
      112/54
  - COWLEY, HENRY WELLESLEY, 1ST BARON, 1773-1847
    - ALS to Sir Thomas Tyrwhitt (1763-1833), 1828 Aug 31 (Box 1)
      St. James Square
      2 p.; 24 x 18 cm.
      Request for a position for his
      servant.
      112/52
  - COWLEY, HENRY WELLESLEY, 1ST BARON, 1773-1847
    - ALS to Sir Thomas Tyrwhitt (1763-1833), 1828 Sep 3 (Box 1)
      Thanks him for considering his
      servant for a post.
      112/53
  - COWLEY, HENRY WELLESLEY, 1ST BARON, 1773-1847
    - ALS to Sir Thomas Tyrwhitt (1763-1833), 1830 Jan 12 (Box 1)
      Regent's Park
      112/55
  - DEVON, WILLIAM REGINALD COURTENAY, 11TH EARL OF, 1807-1888
    - ALS to Sir Thomas Tyrwhitt (1763-1833), 1831 Aug 4 (Box 1)
      House of Lords
      2 p.; 18 x 12 cm.
      Request for a seat for "a very
      pleasing and rather good looking
      Scotchwoman" at his debate.
      112/57
  - DOWNSHIRE, ARTHUR BLUNDELL HILL, 3RD MARQUIS OF, 1788-1845
    - ALS to Sir Thomas Tyrwhitt (1763-1833), [1826 or later] (Box 1)
      Grosnor Court
      On Tyrwhitt's illness and his own
      business.
      112/82
  - DOWNSHIRE, ARTHUR BLUNDELL HILL, 3RD MARQUIS OF, 1788-1845
    - ALS to Sir Thomas Tyrwhitt (1763-1833), n.d. (Box 1)
      Long's Hotel
      Requests his "work upon Turf, coke,
      and Bogs".
      112/83
  - DRY, THOMAS
    - ALS to Sir Thomas Tyrwhitt (1763-1833), 1828 Jul 18 (Box 1)
      Christ Church
      1 p.; 23 x 18 cm.
      Bill for £10.17.0 in dues from the
      butler of Christ Church, Oxford
      University.
      112/76
  - DYMOKE, LEWIS
    - ALS to Sir Thomas Tyrwhitt (1763-1833), n.d. (Box 1)
      1 p.; 22 x 18 cm.
      Request to see him as Tyrwhitt is
      about to be struck off the club list.
      112/86
  - DYMOKE, LEWIS
    - ALS to Sir Thomas Tyrwhitt (1763-1833), 1816 Apr 29 (Box 1)
      London
      3 p.; 22 x 18 cm.
      Informs him that he has paid
      Tyrwhitt's debts at the club.
      112/63
  - DYMOKE, LEWIS
    - ALS to Sir Thomas Tyrwhitt (1763-1833), 1817 Jan 31 (Box 1)
      Grove Street
      3 p.; 20 x 13 cm.
      On the security of his loan.
      112/64
  - DYMOKE, LEWIS
    - ALS to Sir Thomas Tyrwhitt (1763-1833), 1817 Mar 14 (Box 1)
      1 p.; 20 x 13 cm.
      Indicates his "intention to repay
      the money...at the time agreed upon".
      112/65
  - EASTLAKE, WILLIAM
    - ALS to Sir Thomas Tyrwhitt (1763-1833), 1830 Feb 25 (Box 1)
      Plymouth
      3 p.; 25 x 20 cm.
      Discussion of paintings by his
      brother, Sir Charles Locke Eastlake
      (1793-1865).
      112/56
  - ERSKINE, THOMAS ERSKINE, 1ST BARON, 1750-1823
    - ALS to the Prince of Wales, later George IV, king of Gt. Brit. and Ireland (1762-1830), 1802 Apr 21 (Box 1)
      3 p.; 24 x 19 cm.
      Assures the Prince of Wales that his
      petition will be brought before
      George III, king of Gt. Brit.
      (1738-1820).
      112/4
  - GEORGE IV, KING OF GT. BRIT., 1762-1830
    - [Memorandum]: draft in the hand of Sir Thomas Tyrwhitt (1763-1833), 1803 Jan (Box 1)
      Carlton House
      4 p.; 24 x 19 cm.
      Addressed to Henry Addington, 1st
      viscount Sidmouth (1757-1844) and
      concerns the Prince's debts.
      112/6
  - GEORGE IV, KING OF GT. BRIT., 1762-1830
    - [Grant of the Russian order to St. Anne to Sir Thomas Tyrwhitt]: DS, 1824 Sep 11 (Box 1)
      1 p.; 33 x 19 cm. With the king's seal. 112/40
  - GEORGE, PRINCE OF WALES, LATER KING OF GT. BRIT., 1762-1830
    - Letter (draft) to Sir Thomas Tyrwhitt (1763-1833), 1796 Dec 6 (Box 1)
      2 p.; 24 x 19 cm.
      Asks if Tyrwhitt will put his
      petition before George III, king of
      Gt. Brit. (1738-1820).
      112/2
  - GEORGE, PRINCE OF WALES, LATER KING OF GT. BRIT., 1762-1830
    - 2 letters (drafts) in the hand of Sir Thomas Tyrwhitt (1763-1833) to Umdat ul-Umzah, nawab of Arcot and Carnatic, d.1802., [1798] (Box 1)
      9 p.; 19 x 11 cm.
      Welcomes him to British protection
      and presents his sword.
      112/18
  - GRENVILLE, THOMAS, 1755-1846
    - LS to Sir Thomas Tyrwhitt (1763-1833), 1807 Jan 9 (Box 1)
      Admiralty
      1p.; 23 x 19 cm.
      He will try to assist the suggested
      candidates.
      112/46
  - HASTENPFLUG, [?JOHANNES], TREASURER OF WAR
    - [Receipt for £1000], 1799 Sep 30 (Box 1)
      1 p.; 32 x 19 cm. Payment on a loan by Wilhelm, Landgrave of Hesse-Kassel (d.1825) to the Prince of Wales, later George IV, king of Gt. Brit. (1762-1830). 112/35
  - HAYTER, JOHN, 1756-1818
    - ALS to Sir Thomas Tyrwhitt (1763-1833), 1812 Feb 17 (Box 1)
      St. Mary's Hall
      1 p.; 26 x 21 cm.
      On his arrival and first few days at
      Oxford University.
      112/30
  - HEARD, SIR ISAAC, 1730-1822
    - ALS to Sir Thomas Tyrwhitt (1763-1833), 1812 Jul 18 (Box 1)
      College of Arms
      1 p.; 23 x 19 cm.
      Introduction to James Pulman
      (1783-1859).
      112/71
  - HERTFORD, FRANCIS CHARLES, 6TH MARQUIS OF 1777-1842
    - ALS to Sir Thomas Tyrwhitt (1763-1833), [1812] (Box 1)
      15 p.; 24 x 19 cm.
      On the Royal Household.
      112/8
  - HERTFORD, FRANCIS CHARLES, 6TH MARQUIS OF 1777-1842
    - ALS to Sir Thomas Tyrwhitt (1763-1833), n.d. (Box 1)
      On the health of George III, king of
      112/9
  - HOLLAND, ELIZABETH (VASSALL) FOX, BARONESS, 1770-1845
    - ALS to Sir Thomas Tyrwhitt (1763-1833), n.d. (Box 1)
      She is unable to venture forth.
      112/84
  - JERSEY, GEORGE BUSSY VILLIERS, 3RD EARL OF, 1735-1805
    - ALS to Sir Thomas Tyrwhitt (1763-1833), 1799 Feb 9 (Box 1)
      Warwick Street
      1 p.; 24 x 19 cm.
      Bill for £5500.
      112/33
  - JONES, ELIZA TYRWHITT, LADY JONES
    - ALS to Sir Thomas Tyrwhitt (1763-1833), [1827 or later] (Box 1)
      Friendly letter about mutual friends
      and family.
      112/85
  - JONES, ELIZA TYRWHITT, LADY JONES
    - ALS to Sir Thomas Tyrwhitt (1763-1833), 1827 Aug 27 (Box 1)
      Henley Hall
      Request for a position for a protege.
      112/51
  - JONES, SIR T TYRWHITT
    - ALS to Sir Thomas Tyrwhitt (1763-1833) (Box 1)
      Paris
      3 p.; 24 x 18 cm.
      Thanks Tyrwhitt for a report sent
      concerning the writer's son, on his
      way to school at Eton.
      112/80
  - KNIGHTON, SIR WILLIAM, 1ST BART., 1776-1836
    - ALS to Sir Thomas Tyrwhitt (1763-1833), n.d. (Box 1)
      Pavilion
      1 p.; 18 x 12 cm.
      Thank-you note.
      112/58
  - KNIGHTON, SIR WILLIAM, 1ST BART., 1776-1836
    - ALS to Sir Thomas Tyrwhitt (1763-1833), [no yr] Jan 17 (Box 1)
      3 p.; 19 x 12 cm.
      Requests assistance for his friend
      Dr. Goach.
      112/59
  - LONDONDERRY, CHARLES WILLIAM VANE, 3RD MARQUIS OF, 1778-1854
    - ALS to Sir Thomas Tyrwhitt (1763-1833), 1813 Dec 12 (Box 1)
      Frankfurt
      2 p.; 33 x 20 cm.
      Encloses copy of a letter from Karl
      August Fuerst von Hardenberg
      (1750-1822) regarding the arrest of
      Mr. Robinson.
      112/25
  - LYNDHURST, JOHN SINGLETON COPLEY, 1ST BARON, 1772-1863
    - ALS to Sir Thomas Tyrwhitt (1763-1833), n.d. (Box 1)
      1 p.; 20 x 19 cm.
      Suggests he speak to Arthur
      Wellesley, 1st duke of Wellington
      (1769-1852), at Mr. Peel's.
      112/43
  - MACPHERSON, SIR JOHN, 1ST BART., 1745-1821
    - ALS to Sir Thomas Tyrwhitt (1763-1833), 1796 Aug 6 (Box 1)
      Brampton
      Suggests that the Prince Regent,
      later George IV, king of Gt. Brit.
      (1762-1830), write to Umdat ul-Umzah,
      Nawab of Arcot and Carnatic (d.1802).
      112/17
  - MACPHERSON, SIR JOHN, 1ST BART., 1745-1821
    - ALS to Sir Thomas Tyrwhitt (1763-1833), 1800 Aug 28 (Box 1)
      Tunbridge Wells
      4 p.; 19 x 12 cm.
      Comments on the letter from the
      Prince Regent, later George IV, king
      of Gt. Brit. (1762-1830), to Umdat
      ul-Umzah, Nawab of Arcot and
      Carnatic (d.1802).
      112/21
  - MACPHERSON, SIR JOHN, 1ST BART., 1745-1821
    - ALS to Sir Thomas Tyrwhitt (1763-1833), 1801 Jan 2 (Box 1)
      Brompton
      Friendly request for a sum owed.
      112/70
  - MORNINGTON, RICHARD WELLESLEY, 2ND EARL OF, 1760-1842
    - ALS to Sir Thomas Tyrwhitt (1763-1833), 1797 Oct 22 (Box 1)
      Southampton
      4 p.; 25 x 19 cm.
      Promises to deliver the letter from
      the Prince Regent, later George IV,
      king of Gt. Brit. (1762-1830), to
      Umdat ul-Umzah, Nawab of Arcot and
      Carnatic (d.1802); describes Indian
      reactions to European correspondence.
      112/20
  - NEVILE, MR.
    - ALS to Sir Thomas Tyrwhitt (1763-1833), [1827] (Box 1)
      [1827 or later] Oct 6
      Boom St.
      2 p.; 23 x 19 cm.
      On his and Tyrwhitt's claim to the
      Barony of Scrope.
      112/31
  - PULMAN, JAMES, 1783-1859
    - ALS to Sir Thomas Tyrwhitt (1763-1833), 1828 Oct 16 (Box 1)
      Heralds College
      3 p.; 19 x 11 cm.
      Denies that Tyrwhitt or Mr. Nevile
      has any claim to the Barony of
      Scrope.
      112/32
  - ROSSLYN, JAMES ST. CLAIR-ERSKINE, 2ND EARL, 1762-1837
    - Letter (copy) to unnamed recipient, 1807 Dec 6 (Box 1)
      Dyract
      2 p.; 19 x 12 cm.
      Promises to speak to William Shaw,
      1st viscount Cathcart (1755-1843),
      about a Captain's promotion.
      112/47
  - ST. VINCENT, JOHN JERVIS, 1ST EARL, 1735-1823
    - ALS to Sir Thomas Tyrwhitt (1763-1833), 1807 Mar 3 (Box 1)
      Congratulations on the grant to the
      Prince of Wales, later George IV,
      King of Gt. Brit. (1760-1830).
      112/7
  - SIDMOUTH, HENRY ADDINGTON, 1ST VISCOUNT, 1757-1844
    - ALS to Sir Thomas Tyrwhitt (1763-1833), 1816 Jun 7 (Box 1)
      Whitehall
      1 p.; 32 x 19 cm.
      Informs him that the carriage of the
      King of Gt. Brit. (1762-1830), will
      be allowed in St. James's and
      Queen's Parks.
      112/37
  - SIDMOUTH, HENRY ADDINGTON, 1ST VISCOUNT, 1757-1844
    - ALS to Sir Thomas Tyrwhitt (1763-1833), 1818 May 24 (Box 1)
      Clifford St.
      1 p.; 19 x 12 cm.
      Invitation to call at the Home
      Office.
      112/49
  - SINCLAIR, SIR JOHN, 1ST BART., 1754-1835
    - ALS to Sir Thomas Tyrwhitt (1763-1833), 1828 Mar 25 (Box 1)
      Edinburgh
      1 p.; 19 x 11 cm.
      Asks what the role of the government
      will be in "the Fate" of the country.
      112/75
  - SMIRKE, SYDNEY, 1798-1877
    - ALS to Sir Thomas Tyrwhitt (1763-1833), 1829 Oct 23 (Box 1)
      Regent St.
      Tells him the expect a decision from
      the Surveyor General.
      112/45
  - SMITH, SAMUEL, 1766-1841
    - ALS to Sir Thomas Tyrwhitt (1763-1833), 1830 Feb 21 (Box 1)
      2 p.; 19 x 11 cm.
      On the death of Phineas Pett; news
      of his widow.
      112/81
  - THURLOW, EDWARD THURLOW, 1ST BARON, 1731-1806
    - ALS to Sir Thomas Tyrwhitt (1763-1833), 1796 Feb 10 (Box 1)
      Advises Tyrwhitt to act upon his own
      judgment in the absence of the Prince
      of Wales, later George IV, king of
      Gt. Brit. (1760-1830).
      112/1
  - THURLOW, THOMAS
    - ALS to Sir Thomas Tyrwhitt (1763-1833), 1829 Oct 9 (Box 1)
      Boxford Rectory
      He failed to procure the Suffolk
      "Punch."
      112/77
  - THURLOW, THOMAS
    - ALS to Sir Thomas Tyrwhitt (1763-1833), 1829 Oct 21 (Box 1)
      Has found the "Punch" for which he
      was looking.
      112/78
  - TOWNSHEND, CHARLES, 1725-1767
    - ALS to unnamed recipient, 1761 Jun 17 (Box 1)
      Adderbury
      Requests and explanation for his
      resignation.
      112/87
  - TYRWHITT, SIR THOMAS, 1763-1833
    - [Memorandum]: autograph MS, 1802 Dec 11 (Box 1)
      To the Prince of Wales, later George
      IV, King of Gt. Brit. (1762-1830)
      reports on the Chancellor's assurance
      that his petition would be within a
      week before the king, George III,
      King of Gt. Brit. (1738-1820).
      112/5
  - TYRWHITT, SIR THOMAS, 1763-1833
    - Letter (draft) to William Pitt Amherst, 2nd baron, 1773-1857, 1809 Jun 19 (Box 1)
      2 p.; 31 x 20 cm.
      On the request of the Prince of
      Wales, later George IV, king of Gt.
      Brit. (1762-1830), that John Hayter
      (1756-1818) cease work on the
      Herculaneum rolls and return to
      England.
      112/29
  - TYRWHITT, SIR THOMAS, 1763-1833
    - Letter (copy) to Sir Hudson Lowe (1769-1844), 1815 Dec 8 (Box 1)
      On the contract of William Balcombe
      (1779-1829) to provision Napoleon I,
      112/24
  - TYRWHITT, SIR THOMAS, 1763-1833
    - Letter (draft) to Charles William Vane, General Stewart, later 3rd marquis of Londonderry (1778-1854), [1813] (Box 1)
      On the crimes of a Mr. Robinson.
      112/28
  - TYRWHITT, SIR THOMAS, 1763-1833
    - ALS to Edward Thurlow, 1st Baron, 1731-1806, 1797 Feb 13 (Box 1)
      5 p.; 19 x 11 cm.
      On his suggestion to the Prince of
      Brit. (1762-1830), that the Prince
      return to his wife for a male heir.
      112/3
  - UMDAT UL-UMZAH, NAWAB OF ARCOT AND CARNATIC, D.1802
    - LS to the Prince of Wales, later George IV, king of Gt. Brit. (1762-1830), 1797 Mar 21 (Box 1)
      Palace of Chepauck
      10 p.; 33 x 20 cm.
      Thanks him for the sword and his
      interest.
      112/19
  - VANE, SIR H. T.
    - ALS to Sir Thomas Tyrwhitt (1763-1833) (Box 1)
      [1794 or later] Jul 8
      1 p.; 25 x 20 cm.
      Receipt for the £315 on the account
      of the Prince of Wales, later George
      IV, king of Gt. Brit. (1762-1830).
      112/10
  - VIVIAN, RICHARD HUSSEY VIVIAN, 1ST BARON, 1775-1842
    - ALS to Sir Thomas Tyrwhitt (1763-1833), 1815 Feb 12 (Box 1)
      Brighton
      On the usefulness of a Mr. Scott.
      112/60
  - VIVIAN, RICHARD HUSSEY VIVIAN, 1ST BARON, 1775-1842
    - ALS to Sir Thomas Tyrwhitt (1763-1833), 1815 Feb 14 (Box 1)
      Quotes a letter of support by his
      father, John Vivian (d.1826).
      112/61
  - VIVIAN, RICHARD HUSSEY VIVIAN, 1ST BARON, 1775-1842
    - ALS to Francis Ingram-Seymour-Conway, 5th marquis of Hertford (1743-1822), 1815 Feb 14 (Box 1)
      Assurance that Mr. Scott "is a clean
      fellow".
      112/62
  - WEYMSS, FRANCIS CHARTERIS-WEYMSS-DOUGLAS, 1ST BARON, 1772-1853
    - ALS to Sir Thomas Tyrwhitt (1763-1833), 1829 Feb 21 (Box 1)
      12 p.; 22 x 18 cm.
      Promises political support for the
      king, George IV, King of Gt. Brit.
      (1762-1830).
      112/42
  - WILHELM IX, LANDGRAVE OF HESSE-KASSEL, D.1825
    - LS to Sir Thomas Tyrwhitt (1763-1833), 1799 Sep 7 (Box 1)
      Wilhelmshoehe
      Due to his lack of funds, he
      apparently accepts Tyrwhitt's
      suggestion for a means of repayment.
      112/34
  - WILHELM IX, LANDGRAVE OF HESSE-KASSEL, D.1825
    - LS to Sir Thomas Tyrwhitt (1763-1833), 1800 Jun 28 (Box 1)
      1 p.; 23 x 20 cm.
      Identifies his counselor of war as
      [Johann Wilhelm?] Buderus.
      112/36
  - WITTGENSTEIN, WILHELM LUDWIG GEORG, GRAF, 1770-1851
    - ALS to Sir Thomas Tyrwhitt (1763-1833), 1813 Nov 19 (Box 1)
      Berlin
      The confession of a Mr. Robinson in
      German with a partial translation.
      112/27
  - WRAXALL, SIR NATHANIEL WILLIAM, 1ST BART., 1751-1831
    - Letter (copy) to Charles Arbuthnot (1767-1850), 1813 Feb 13 (Box 1)
      Ramsgate
      Claims to be misunderstood, points
      out that the Prince Regent, later
      George IV, King of Gt. Brit.
      (1762-1830), desires him to be made
      a baronet.
      112/12
  - WRAXALL, SIR NATHANIEL WILLIAM, 1ST BART., 1751-1831
    - ALS to Sir Thomas Tyrwhitt (1763-1833), 1813 Feb 10 (Box 1)
      On the rejection of his claim to the
      Baronetcy.
      112/13
  - WRAXALL, SIR NATHANIEL WILLIAM, 1ST BART., 1751-1831
    - ALS to Sir Thomas Tyrwhitt (1763-1833), 1813 Feb 16 (Box 1)
      4 p.; 22 x 18 cm.
      Thanks him and explains in detail
      what he believes are the reasons for
      his failure to receive a Baronetcy.
      112/14
  - WRAXALL, SIR NATHANIEL WILLIAM, 1ST BART., 1751-1831
    - ALS to Sir Thomas Tyrwhitt (1763-1833), 1813 Feb 17 (Box 1)
      On the infidelity of Caroline Amelia
      Elizabeth, queen consort of George
      IV, king of Gt. Brit. (1768-1821).
      112/15
  - WRAXALL, SIR NATHANIEL WILLIAM, 1ST BART., 1751-1831
    - ALS to Sir Thomas Tyrwhitt (1763-1833), 1813 Feb 22 (Box 1)
      What the Prince Regent, later George
      IV, king of Gt. Brit. (1762-1830),
      should do regarding the infidelity
      of his wife, Caroline Amelia
      IV, (1768-1821).
      112/16